Valerie Raghoebier | 778-223-0769 | valerie.raghoebier@outlook.com https://hummingbirdjs101.github.io/Valerie-Raghoebier/ | Vancouver, BC

Summary

Highly motivated professional with 5+ years of experience in the STEM industry with a proven ability to develop and implement strategies that support business and financial objectives. Recognized as an expert in applying user experience to applications.

Skills

Technical

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, FLASK
- Git, GitHub, VS Code, Linux, Bash
- MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint), Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe XD), Figma

Communications & Customer Relations

- Languages: Dutch, English, Portuguese, Hindi and Spanish
- Teambuilding and leadership

Work Experience

Software Developer, reSolved, Toronto (remote), 2023-2024

- Collaborated with clients to gather and understand user stories, objectives, and requirements.
- Conducted thorough analysis of user requirements to ensure clarity and feasibility.
- Supported and built client-specific solutions on the SmartSimple platform, a cloud-based tracking and reporting platform that helps organizations automate their critical processes.
- Provided training and support to clients on using and maintaining front-end interfaces effectively.

Frontend Developer/Designer, Freelancer, Vancouver, BC, 2022- 2023

- Translated client ideas into wireframes, mockups, and prototypes, incorporating user feedback for iterative design improvements.
- Solicited feedback from clients post-delivery to assess satisfaction levels and identify areas for improvement.

Data Analyst, ehsAl, Vancouver, BC, 2020-2023

 Mastered advanced Microsoft Excel to create pivot tables and reports. Conceptualized strategies for machine learning data and collaborated with team leads for process improvement

Education & Training

Ready to Rise, ETHOS Career Management Group Ltd., Duncan, BC 2023 Business Communications and Problem Solving in the Workplace

Bachelor of Science, Anton De Kom University, Paramaribo, Suriname 2009-2013 Majored in Mineral Resources Management with a minor in Computer Science

Volunteer Experience

•	Rainbow Refugees: Supports the LGBTQ+ refugee community by donating time and skills to their
	awareness, advocacy and fundraising related activities and workshops.